Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: July 20, 2016
- MALE FISH: Wow.
- FEMALE FISH: Mmm.
- Wow.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Yes, Marlin.
No, I see it. It's beautiful.
So, Coral, when you said
you wanted an ocean view,
you didn't think that we're going
to get the whole ocean, did you? Huh?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Oh, yeah!
A fish can breathe out here. Did
your man deliver or did he deliver?
- My man delivered.
- And It wasn't so easy.
Because a lot of other clownfish
had their eyes on this place.
You better believe they did.
Every single one of them.
Mmm-hm. You did good and the
neighbourhood is awesome.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER, LAUGHTER)
- So you do like it, don't you?
- No, no, I do, I do, I really do like it.
But, Marlin, I know that
the Drop Off is desirable,
with a great schools
and the amazing view and all...
but do we really
need so much space?
Coral, honey, these are our
kids we're talking about.
They deserve the best.
Look, look, look.
They'll wake up, poke their little
heads out and they see a whale!
- See right by their bedroom window!
- (CHUCKLES) Shh!
- You're going to wake the kids.
- Oh, right. Right.
Aw, look.
They're dreaming.
- We still have to name them.
- You want to name all of them? Right now?
All right. We'll name
this half Marlin Jr.
And then this half Coral Jr.
- Okay, we're done.
- I like Nemo.
Nemo?
We'll name one Nemo, but I'd like
most of them to be Marlin Jr.
Just think in a couple of days,
we're going to be parents!
Yeah.
- What if they don't like me?
- Marlin...
- No, really.
- There's over 400 eggs.
Odds are one of them
is bound to like you.
What?
- You remember how we met?
- Well, I try not to.
Well, I remember.
Excuse me, Miss. Can you check
if I have a hook in my lip?
- Marlin.
- Oh, you gotta look closer.
- (SQUEALS) Get away! Get away!
- Here he is. Cutie's here!
Where did everybody go?
Coral. Get inside
the house, Coral.
No, no, Coral, don't.
They'll be fine. Just get inside.
You. Right now.
No! Ow!
(MARLIN GROANS)
Coral!
Coral? Coral?
(GASPS)
(SOBS, VOICE BREAKING)
Coral! Coral?
Coral?
There, there, there.
It's okay. Daddy's here.
Daddy's got you.
I promise I will never let
anything happen to you,
Nemo.
First day of school! Wake up! Wake up!
Come on. First day of school.
I don't want to go to school.
Five more minutes.
- Not you, Dad. Me.
- Okay.
- Get up! Get up! Time for school!
- Huh? What is...?
- All right, I'm up. It's time for school.
- Oh, boy! Oh, boy! Whoa!
Nemo!
- First day of school!
- Nemo, don't move. Don't move!
You'll never get out of
there yourself. I'll... I'll do it.
All right, where's the break?
You feel a break? No.
Sometimes you can't talk because fluid
is rushing to the area. Now, any rushing fluids?
- No. No.
- Are you whoozy? How many stripes do I have?
- Answer the stripe question.
- I'm fine. Three.
No! See! Something's wrong with you.
I have one, two...
Three. That's all I have? Oh.
You're okay.
How's the lucky fin?
- Lucky.
- Let's see.
Now, you sure want to go to school
this year? There's no problem if you don't.
- You can wait five or six years.
- Come on, Dad. It's time for school.
- Forgot to brush.
- (SIGHS)
Do you want this
anemone to sting you?
- Yes. (GROANS)
- Brush.
- Okay. I'm done.
- You missed a spot.
- Where?
- There.
- (LAUGHING)
- Right there. And here and here.
We're excited. First day of school. Here we go.
We're ready to learn to get some knowledge.
Now, what's the one thing we have
to remember about the ocean?
- It's not safe.
- That's my boy.
So, first: we check to see that the coast
is clear. We go out and back in.
And then we go out
and back in.
And then one more time.
Out and back in.
- If you want to do it four times...
- Dad...
All right. Come on, boy.
Dad, maybe while I'm at school,
I'll see a shark.
- I highly doubt that.
- Have you ever met a shark?
- No, and I don't plan to.
- How old are sea turtles?
Sea turtles?
I... I don't know.
Sandy Plankton from
next door he said that
sea turtles said (STAMMERS)
they live to be about 100 years old.
If I ever meet a sea turtle, I'll ask him,
after I'm done talking to the shark.
Okay? Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on. Wait to cross.
Hold my fin. Hold my fin.
Dad, you're not going to freak out
like you did at the petting zoo, are you?
Hey, that snail
was about to charge.
Hmm. I wonder where we're
supposed to go.
- FISHES: Bye, Mom.
- I'll pick you up after school.
Come on, you guys. Stop it.
Give it back.
Come on. We'll try over there.
Excuse me. Is this where
we meet his teacher?
- Well, look who's out of the anemone.
- Yes, shocking, I know.
- Marty, right?
- Marlin.
- Bob.
- Ted.
Phil. Hey, you're
a clownfish.
You're funny, right?
Hey, tell us a joke.
- Yeah. Good idea.
- (ALL AGREEING)
Well, acutally that's a common misconception.
Clownfish are no funnier than any other fish.
- Aw, Come on, Clowny.
- Yeah, do something funny.
- Yeah!
- All right. I know one joke.
There's a mollusk.
See, and he walks up to...
Well, he doesn't walk up,
he swims up.
But, actually, the mollusk isn't
moving. He's in one place.
And then the sea cucumber...
Well, they...
I'm mixed up. There was a
mollusk and a sea cucumber.
None of them were walking...
Sheldon! Get out of
Mr. Johanssen's yard now!
All right, you kids!
Where'd you go? Where'd you go?
Where'd you go?
Dad, dad. Can I go
play, too? Can I?
I would feel better if you go
play over on the sponge beds.
- (MOTHER GASPS)
- (BABY CRIES)
That's where I would play.
- What's wrong with his fin?
- He looks funny.
- Hey, what did I do? What did I do?
- Be nice. It's his first time at school.
He was born with it, kids.
We call it his lucky fin.
Dad...
See this tentacle? It's actually shorter
than all my other tentacles.
But you can't really tell. Especially
when I twirl them like this.
I'm an H20 intolerant.
I'm obnoxious.
♪ Let's name the zones,
the zones, the zones ♪
♪ Let's name the zones
of the open sea ♪
Mr. Ray!
- Come on, Nemo.
- Oh, you better stay with me.
♪ There's epipelagic, mesopelagic,
bathyal, abyssopelagic ♪
♪ All the rest are too
deep for you and me to see ♪
Huh? I wonder where
my class has gone.
ALL: We're under here.
Aw, There you are!
Come aboard, explorers.
♪ Knowledge exploring
is oh so lyrical ♪
♪ When you think thoughts
that are empirical  ♪
Dad, you can go now.
- Well, hello. Who is this?
- I'm Nemo.
Nemo, all new explorers must
answer a science question.
- Okay.
- You live in what kind of home?
In an anemoninny.
Anemonemenemone.
Okay, okay, don't hurt yourself.
Welcome aboard, explorerer!
Just so you know,
he's got a little fin.
If he's having trouble swimming,
let him take a break. 10-15 minutes.
Dad, it's time for
you to go now.
Don't worry. We're going
to stay together as a group.
Okay, class. Optical
orbits up front.
Remember, we keep our supraesophageal
ganglion to ourselves.
- That means you, Jimmy.
- Oh, man!
- Bye, Nemo.
- Bye, Dad.
Bye, son.
Be safe.
Hey, you're doing pretty well
for a first-timer.
Well, you can't hold on to
them forever, can you?
I had a tough time when my
eldest went out on the Drop Off.
The Drop Off! They're
going to the Drop Off?
What? Are you insane?
Why don't we just fry them up now
and serve them with chips?
Hey, Marty, calm down.
Don't tell me to
be calm, pony-boy.
Pony-boy?
You know for a clownfish,
he really isn't that funny.
Pity.
♪ Let's name the species,
the species, the species ♪
♪ Let's name the species
that live in the sea ♪
♪ Mollusca and gastropoda,
arthropoda, echinoderma, chordata ♪
♪ And some fish
like you and me! ♪
Come on. Sing with me.
♪ Seaweed is cool,
seaweed is fun ♪
♪ It makes its food from
the rays of the sun  ♪
Okay, the Drop Off.
All right, kids. Feel free
to explore, but stay close.
(GASPS) Stromatolitic
cyanobacteria! Gather.
An entire ecosystem contained in
one infinitesimal speck.
(CONTINUES TALKING)
Come on. Let's go.
Come on. Sing with me.
♪ There's porifera, coelenterata,
hydrozoa, scyphozoa ♪
♪ Anthozoa, ctenophora,
bryozoas three  ♪
Hey, guys, wait up.
Whoa!
Cool.
- Saved your life!
- Ahh! Oh.
- You guys made me ink.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
What's that?
I know what that is. Oh, Oh!
Sandy Plankton saw one.
He called... He said
it was called a butt.
Wow. That's a pretty big butt.
Oh! Look at me. I'm gonna go
touch the butt.
(LAUGHTER)
Oh, yeah? Let's see
you get closer.
Okay.
Beat that.
Come on, Nemo.
How far can you go?
- My dad says it's not safe.
- Nemo, no!
Dad?
You were about to
swim into open water.
No! I wasn't gonna go out...
It was just a good thing I was here.
If I haven't shown up, I don't...
- Sorry, he wasn't going to go.
- Yeah, he was too afraid.
- No, I wasn't.
- This does not concern you kids.
And you're lucky I don't tell your parents
you were out there. You know you can't swim well.
- I can swim fine, Dad, okay?
- No. It's not okay.
You shouldn't be
anywhere near here.
Okay, I was right. You know what?
You'll start school in a year or two.
No, dad. Just because you're
scared of the ocean...
Clearly you're not ready.
And you're not coming back until you are.
You think you can do these
things, but you just can't, Nemo!
I hate you.
♪ There's...  ♪
Nothing to see.
Gather, uh, over there.
Excuse me? Is there anything I can do?
I am a scientist, sir. Is there any problem?
You know, I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to interrupt things. He isn't a good swimmer.
And I just think it's a little too soon
for him to be out here unsupervised.
MR. RAY: Well, I can assure you,
he's quite safe with me.
MARLIN: Look, I'm sure he is.
But you have a large class and
he can get lost, you know, from sight
if you're not looking.
I'm not saying you're not looking...
Oh, my gosh! Nemo's
swimming out to sea.
Nemo!
What do you think
you're doing?
You're gonna get stuck
out there
and I'm gonna have to get you
before another fish does.
Get back here.
I said get back here now!
Stop.
You take one more
move, mister...
Don't you dare. If you put
one fin on that boat...
Are you listening to me?
Don't touch the boa...
Nemo!
He touched the butt.
You just paddle your little tail
right back here, Nemo.
That's right. You are in
big trouble, young man.
Do you hear me? Big...
Aagghh!
Daddy, help me!
I'm coming, Nemo.
Get under me, kids.
No! Dad! Daddy!
Nemo!
Nemo! Nemo, no!
Nemo, Nemo!
No!
(FRIGHTENED GABBLING)
Hold on!
(MARLIN PANTING)
Oh, no.
No. No, It's gone. It's gone.
No, no! It can't be gone.
No. No!
Nemo! Nemo...
Nemo!
No.
Nemo! Nemo!
No. Please, no.
No, no.
Has anybody seen a boat?
- Please. A white boat?
- (FISHES CLAMORING)
He took my son! My son!
Help me. Please.
- Look out!
- Ahh!
Oh, sorry. I didn't
see you, Sir.
Are you okay?
- He's gone. He's gone.
- There, there.
- No, He's gone. He's gone.
- It's all right.
- It'll be okay.
- No, no, they took him away.
I gotta have to find the boat.
- A boat? Hey, I've seen a boat.
- You have?
- Uh-huh, and it passed by not too long ago.
- A white one?
- Hi. I'm Dory.
- Where? Which way?
Oh. Oh, oh, oh! It went, um, this way.
It went this way!
- Follow me.
- Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you so much.
No problem.
Wait.
Will you quit it? I'm trying to swim here.
What, ocean big enough for you?
Something like that? You got
a problem, buddy? Huh? Huh?
Do you? Do you? Do you?
Want a piece of me?
Yeah. Yeah.
Ooh! I'm scared now! What!?
- Wait a minute...
- Stop following me, okay?
What are you talking about? You're showing
me which way the boat went.
A boat? Hey, I've seen a boat.
It passed by not too long ago.
It went, um, this way.
It went this way! Follow me!
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
What is going on?
You already told me which
way the boat was going.
I did? Oh, no.
If this is some kind of practical joke,
it's not funny and I know funny.
- I'm a clownfish.
- No, it's not. I know it's not. I'm so sorry.
See, I suffer from
short-term memory loss.
Short-term memory loss?
- I don't believe this.
- No. It's true.
I forget things almost
instantly. It runs in my family.
Well, at least I think it does.
Uh... Hmm?
Where are they?
Can I help you?
Something's wrong with you.
Really.
You're wasting my time.
I have to find my son.
Hello.
Well, hi!
Name's Bruce.
It's all right. I understand.
Why trust a shark, right?
(LAUGHING)
So, what's a couple of bites
like you doing out so late, eh?
Nothing. We're not doing anything.
We're not even out.
Great.
Then how would you morsels like to come
to a little get-together I'm having?
- You mean like a party?
- Yeah. Yeah, right. A party.
- What do you say?
- I love parties. That sounds like fun.
You know, Parties are fun
and it's tempting, but we can't because...
Oh, Come on. I insist.
Okay. That's all that matters.
DORY: Hey, Look. Balloons.
It is a party.
Mind your distance, though.
Those balloons can be a bit dodgy.
You wouldn't want
one of them to pop.
Anchor! Chum!
There you are, Bruce. Finally.
- We got company.
- Oh, It's about time, mate.
We've already gone through
the snacks and I'm still starving.
We almost had to have
a feeding frenzy.
Come on. Let's get this over with.
(BELL DINGS)
Right then. The meeting has
officially come to order.
Let us all say the pledge.
ALL: I am a nice shark,
not a mindless eating machine.
If I am to change this image,
I must first change myself.
Fish are friends, not food.
Except stinking dolphins.
Dolphins! Yeah,
they think they're so cute.
Oh, Look at me, I'm a flipping little dolphin.
Let me flip for you. Ain't I something?
Right then, today's meeting is
step five "Bring a Fish Friend".
- Now, Do you all have your friends?
- Got mine.
- DORY: Hey there!
- BRUCE: How about you, Chum?
Oh. Well, I seem to
have misplaced my
- friend.
- (MARLIN GASPS)
BRUCE: It's all right, Chum.
You can help yourself
to one of my friends.
Oh. Thanks, mate.
A little chum for Chum, eh?
I'll start the testimonies.
Hello. My name is Bruce.
ANCHOR & CHUM:
Hello, Bruce.
It has been three weeks since
my last fish, on my honour,
or may I be chopped up
and made into soup.
- You're an inspiration to all of us.
- Amen.
- Right, then. Who's next?
- Oh, Oh! Pick me. Pick me. Pick me!
- Yes, The little Sheila down the front.
- Whoo!
Come on up here.
Hi. I'm Dory.
SHARKS: Hello, Dory.
And... Well, I don't think
I've ever eaten a fish.
- All right, that's incredible, Dory.
- Good on you, mate!
I'm glad I got
that off my chest.
All right. Anyone else? Hello, how about
you, mate? What's your problem?
Me? I don't...
I don't have a problem.
- Oh? Okay.
- SHARKS: Denial.
Just start with your name.
Okay. Uh, Hello.
My name is Marlin.
I'm a clownfish.
- A clownfish? Really?
- Go on. Tell us a joke.
Ooh! I love jokes.
Well, I actually do know one
that's pretty good.
There was this mollusk and he
walks up to a sea cucumber.
Normally they don't talk, sea cucumbers,
but in a joke, everyone talks.
So, the sea mollusk says
to the cucumber...
Daddy!
Nemo!
Nemo! Ha-ha-ha! Nemo!
- I don't get it.
- For a clownfish he's not that funny.
No, no, no, he's my son.
He was taken by these divers.
(GASPS)
Oh, my. You poor fish.
- Humans. Think they own everything.
- Probably American.
(TEARFULLY) Now, there is a father
looking for his little boy.
MARLIN: Ugh! What do these
markings mean?
- (SOBS) I never knew my father.
- Come here.
- We're all mates here, mate.
- I can't read human.
Well, then we gotta find a fish
that can read this. Hey, Look. Sharks!
- Guys. Guys, guys.
- No, no, no, Dory. No, Dory.
- Hey, that's mine. Give it back. Gimme!
- Dory, Cut it out.
- Ow! Ow, ow!
- Oh, I'm sorry. Are you okay? I'm so sorry.
You really clocked me there.
Am I bleeding?
Dory, are you oka... (SNIFFS)
Oh! Oh!
That's good.
BOTH: (GASPS)
Intervention!
- Just a bite.
- You hold it together, mate.
- Fish are friends, not food.
- Food!
- Dory, look out.
- Ahh!
I'm having fish tonight.
Remember the steps, mate.
Just one bite.
G'day.
There's no way out.
There's gotta be a way to escape.
- Who is it?
- Dory, help me find a way out.
Sorry. You'll have to come back later.
We're trying to escape.
Okay. There's no way out.
There's gotta be a way out.
Look, here's something. "Es-ca-pé."
I wonder what that means. It's funny...
- It's spelled just like the word "escape."
- Let's go.
Here's Brucie!
- Wait a minute. You can read?
- I can read? That's right! I can read!
Well, then here. Read this now.
He really doesn't mean it. You know,
he never even knew his father.
Don't fall off the wagon.
Oh, no! It's blocked.
No, Bruce! Focus!
Sorry about... Bruce, mate.
He's really... A nice guy.
I need to get that mask.
You want that mask? Okay.
- No, no, no, no!
- Whoo!
Quick. Grab the mask. Grab it!
Oh, no. Bruce.
What?
Swim away! Swin away!
DORY: Oh, Is the party over?
(DINGS)
Nice.
Dad?!
Daddy?
- DR. PHILIP: Barbara.
- BARBARA: Uh-huh?
Prep for his anterior
crown, would you, please?
- And I really need a few more cotton rolls.
- Okay.
Hello, little fella.
Beauty, isn't he?
I found that guy struggling
for life off at the reef, and I saved him.
- So, that Novocain kicked in yet?
- (PATIENT GABBLES)
Bubbles!
- My bubbles.
- He likes bubbles.
No, no, no, no!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Bonjour.
- Aagghh!
Slow down, little fella.
There's nothing to worry about.
- Oh, he's scared to death.
- I want to go home.
Do you know where
my dad is?
Honey, your dad's probably
back at the pet store.
- Pet store?
- Yeah.
- Like I'm from Bob's Fish Mart.
- Pet Palace.
- Fish-O-Rama.
- Mail order.
E-Bay.
- So, which one is it?
- I'm from the ocean.
Ah, the ocean. The ocean!
Aagghh!
He hasn't been
decontaminated yet. Jacques!
- Clean him!
- Oui. Oui.
- Ocean.
- Ooh, La mer.
Voilà. He is clean.
Wow. The big blue.
What's it like?
Uh... Big and blue?
I knew it.
Kid, If there's anything you need,
just ask your Auntie Deb. That's me.
Or If I'm not around you can always talk
to my sister, Flo. Hi. How are you?
Don't listen to anything my
sister says. She's nuts.
(MUFFLED)
- Can't hear you, Peach.
- I said we got a live one.
- Yes!
- Boy, oh, boy.
- What have we got?
- Root canal. And by the looks of those X-Rays.
It's not gonna be pretty.
Aagghh!
- Repedemic Clamp installed?
- Yup.
- What did he use to open?
- Glader Glidden drill.
- He seems to be favouring that one latey.
- Ugh, I can't see, Flo.
(MUMBLING)
Agh!
- Now, he's doing The Schilder Technique.
- Oh, he's using a Hedstrom file.
That's not a Hedstrom file.
That's a K-Flex.
It's got a teardrop cross section.
Clearly, a Hedstrom.
- No, no. K-Flex! K-Flex!
- Hedstrom! Hedstrom!
There I go. Little help.
Over here.
I'll go deflate him.
(BLOAT DEFLATING)
All right. Go ahead and rinse.
Ugh! The human mouth
is a disgusting place.
- Hey, Nigel.
- What did I Miss? Am I late?
- Root canal. And it's a doozy.
- Root Canal, huh? What did he use to open?
- Glader Glidden drill.
- He's been favouring that one.
I hope he doesn't get surplus
sealer at the portal terminus.
- Hello. Who's this?
- New guy.
- The dentist took him off the reef.
- An outie.
From my neck of the woods, eh?
Sorry if I ever took a snap at you.
- Fish gotta swim. Birds gotta eat.
- Hey! No, no, no!
Those aren't your fish. They're my fish.
Come on. Go! Go, on! Shoo! Shoo!
The picture broke.
This here's Darla. She's my niece.
She's gonna be eight this week.
Hey, little fella. Say hello
to your new mummy.
She's gonna be here
Friday to pick you up.
You're her present.
Oh, Shh, Shh, Shh!
It's our little secret.
Well, Mr. Tucker,
while that sets up, I'm going to
go see a man about a wallaby.
Oh, Darla!
- What? What's wrong with her?
- She wouldn't stop shaking the bag.
- Poor Chuckles.
- He was her present last year.
Hitched a ride on the
porcelain express.
She's a fish killer.
I can't go with that girl.
I have to get back to my dad.
- Daddy! Help me!
- Oh, he's stuck.
Nobody touch him!
Nobody touch him.
Can you help me?
No. You got yourself in there,
you can get yourself out.
- Ugh, Gill...
- I just want to see him do it, okay?
Calm down. Now, alternate wiggling
your fins and your tail.
I can't. I have a bad fin.
Never stopped me.
Just think about
what you need to do.
Come on.
Perfect.
- You did it.
- Good squirming.
Wow, from the ocean!
Just like you, Gill.
Yeah.
I've seen that look before.
What are you thinking about?
I'm thinking tonight we give
the kid a proper reception.
- Okay, kid, you got a name or what?
- Nemo.
I'm Nemo.
Nemo. Nemo.
DORY: (IN SLEEP)
Are you gonna eat that?
Hey, careful with that hammer.
- Dory!
- Sea-Monkey has my money.
Wake up. Get up. Come on!
Get up!
- Come on.
- Yes, I'm a natural blue.
- Get up!
- Look out. Sharks eat fish!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(COUGHING)
Wow. Dusty.
The mask. Where's the mask?
No! No, the mask! Get it!
Get the mask!
Get the mask! Get it!
(PANTING)
(DORY SCATTING)
Whoo-hoo! La-la-la-la.
Just keeps going on,
doesn't it?
Echo! Echo!
- Hey, what are you doing?
- It's gone. I've lost the mask.
- What, did you drop it?
- You dropped it!
That was my only chance of
finding my son. Now it's gone.
Hey, Mr. Grumpy Gills.
When life gets you down,
you know what you gotta do?
- I don't want to know, what you gotta do.
- ♪ Just keep swimming ♪
♪ Just keep swimming,
swimming, swimming ♪
♪ What do we do?
We swim, swim ♪
- Dory, no singing.
- Ho-ho-ho-ho-ho!
♪ I love to swim ♪
♪ And when you want to
swim you want to...  ♪
See, I'm gonna get stuck now,
with that song. Now, It's in my head!
DORY: Sorry.
- MARLIN: Dory, do you see anything?
- DORY: Something's got me!
- That was me. I'm Sorry.
- Who's that?
Who could it be? It's me.
DORY: Are... Are
you my conscience?
MARLIN: Yeah, yeah.
I'm your conscience.
We haven't spoken for a while.
How are you?
- Oh, Can't complain.
- Yeah, good.
Now, Dory, I want you to tell me,
do you see anything?
I see a...
- I see a light.
- A light?
Yeah. Over there.
Hey, conscience, am I dead?
I see it, too.
What is it?
It's so pretty!
I...
I'm feeling happy.
Which is a big deal for me.
I want to touch it.
Hey, come back.
Come on back here.
- I'm gonna get you.
- I'm gonna get you. I'm gonna get you.
- ♪ I'm going to swim with you ♪
♪ I'm going to be
your best friend  ♪
Good feeling's gone.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
I can't see. I don't know
where I'm going.
- The mask!
- Ugh. What mask?
Okay. I can't see a thing.
Whoa, geez.
- Hey, look. A mask.
- Read it!
Uh, I'm sorry, but if you could bring it
a little closer. I kinda need the light.
That's great.
Keep it right there.
- Just read it!
- Okay, okay.
Mr. Bossy.
"P." Okay. P.
"Sher..."
P. Sher... P. Shirley...
P not Shirley.
Oh! The first line's
"P. Sherman."
"P. Sherman"
doesn't make any sense!
Okay, Uh, second line.
- "42... 42..."
- Don't eat me. Don't eat me.
DORY: Light, please.
- "Walla... Wallaby."
- (MARLIN MUFFLED MUMBLING)
The second line's
"42 Wallaby Way."
That's great! Just finish up, here.
Speed read. Take your time. No pressure.
There's a lot of pressure!
Take a guess, now! With pressure.
- Sydney. It's Sydney!
- Duck!
MARLIN: (PANTS)
I'm dead. I'm dead.
I died. I'm dead.
Whoo-hoo!
♪ We did it, we did it ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ No eating here tonight, whoo!
eating here tonight ♪
♪ No, no, no, eating here tonight
You're on a diet  ♪
Dory. Dory. What did it say?
What did the mask say?
P. Sherman, 42 Wallaby Way,
Sydney. (GASPS)
I remembered what it said! I usually
forget things, but I remembered it that time.
- P. Sherman...
- Wait! Where is that?
I don't know. But who cares?
Ha-ha! I remembered.
P. Sherman, 42 Wallaby Way,
Sydney. I remembered it again!
Psst!
(WHISPERS)
Nemo.
Nemo!
Huh?
Suivez-moi.
Follow me.
(POLYNESIAN-TYPE CHANTING)
ALL: Hoo!
State your name.
Nemo.
Brother Bloat, proceed.
Nemo, newcomer of
orange and white.
You have been called forth to the
summit of Mount Wannahockaloogie
to join with us in the
fraternal bonds of tankhood.
Huh?
- We want you in our club, kid.
- Really?
If you are able
to swim through...
the Ring of Fire!
Turn on the Ring of Fire. The Ring of Fire.
You said you could do it.
The Ring of Fire!
(CHANTING RESUMES)
Bubbles, bubbles. Let me...
Isn't there another way?
He's just a boy.
(CHANTING SPEEDS UP)
From this moment on, you will
now be known as Sharkbait.
Sharkbait! Oo-ha-ha!
Welcome, Brother Sharkbait.
- Enough with the Sharkbait.
- Sharkbait, oo-ba-badoo...
- Okay, Sharkbait's one of us now. Agreed?
- Agreed.
And we can't send him to his death.
Darla's coming in five days.
So what are we gonna do?
I'll tell you what we're
gonna do.
We're going to get him out of here.
We're gonna help him escape.
- Escape? Really?
- We're all going to escape.
Gill, please. Not another
one of your escape plans.
Sorry, but they just...
they never work.
Yeah, why should this
be any different?
- 'Cause we've got him.
- Me?
- You see that filter?
- Yeah.
You're the only one who can
get in and out of that thing.
What we need you to do, is to take
a pebble inside there and jam the gears.
You do that and this tank's going
to get filthier and filthier by the minute.
Pretty soon the dentist
will have to clean the tank himself.
And when he does, he'll take us out
of the tank, put us in individual baggies,
then we'll roll ourselves down
the counter, out of the window,
off the awning, into the bushes,
across the street and into the harbour.
It's foolproof.
- Who's with me?
- I.
- I think you're nuts.
- (SIGHS)
No offense, kid, but you're not
the best swimmer.
He's fine. He can do this.
So, Sharkbait,
what do you think?
Let's do it!
P. Sherman, 42 Wallaby Way,
Sydney. Where are you going?
I'm going to P. Sherman, 42
Wallaby Way, Sydney.
If you ask where I'm going,
I'll tell you this. Where I'm going is...
P. Sherman, 42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Where? I'm sorry. I didn't hear you.
Excuse me.
Ex... Excuse me. Uhm.
Hi. Do you know
how to get... Hello?
Wait. Wait.
Can you tell me... Hey!
Hold it!
Wait a minute.
I'm trying to talk to you.
Okay, fellas.
Come back here, please.
One quick question. I need to...
And they're gone again.
P. Sherman, 42
Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Why do I have to tell you
over and over again? I'll tell you again.
- I don't get tired of it. P. Sher...
- All right. All right, here's the thing.
I think it's best if
I just carry on from here by...
- By myself.
- Okay.
- You know. Alone.
- Uh-huh.
Without... Well, not without you,
but I don't want you with me.
- Huh?
- Am I... I don't want to hurt your feelings.
- You want me to leave?
- Well, I mean not... Yes. Yeah.
It's just you know, I just can't
afford any more delays.
And you're one of those fish
that 'cause delays.
Sometimes it's a good thing.
There's a whole group of fish.
- They're delay fish.
- You mean...
- You mean you don't like me?
- No, of course I like you.
It's because I like you
I don't want to be with you.
It's a complicated emotion.
Don't cry. I like you.
Hey, you!
Lady, is this guy
bothering you?
- I don't remember. Were you?
- No, no, no. We're just...
Hey, do you guys know
how I can get to...
Look, pal. We're talking to the lady,
not you. Hey, hey. You like impressions?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay. Just like in
rehearsals, gentlemen.
So, what are we? Take a guess.
- DORY: Ooh, I've seen one of those.
- I'm a fish with a nose like a sword.
- Wait. Wait, um...
- It's a swordfish.
Hey, clown-boy,
let the lady guess.
Where's the butter?
- It's on the tip of my tongue.
- Lobster.
- Saw that.
- What?
- Lots of legs.
- DORY: Clam?
Close enough.
♪ Oh, It's a whale of a tale
I'll tell you, lad  ♪
- Oh, They're good.
- Would somebody please give me directions?
- "Would somebody please give me directions?"
- (DORY LAUGHING)
- I'm serious.
- Blah, blah, me, me, blah.
Blah, blah, blah, me, me, me.
Thank you.
Oh, dear. Hey.
Hey, come back.
- Hey, what's the matter?
- What's the matter?
Well, they're doing their
silly little impressions,
I am miles from home
with a fish that can't even
remember her own name.
- Well, I bet that's frustrating.
- Meanwhile, my son is out there.
- Your son Chico? Right got it.
- Nemo.
It doesn't matter. 'Cause no fish
in this entire ocean is gonna help me.
Well, I'm helping you.
Wait right here.
- Guys.
- What? Is he bothering you again?
No, no, he's a good guy.
Go easy on him.
He's lost his son Fabio.
Any of you heard of P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney?
Sydney? Oh, sure.
Ted here's got relatives
in Sydney. Don't you, Ted?
- TED: Sure do.
- Ooh. Hey, they know Sydney!
- You wouldn't know how to get there? Would you?
- What you wanna do is follow the EAC.
That's, uh,
East Australian Current.
Big current. You can't Miss it.
It's in...
that direction.
And then you gotta
follow that for about, I don't know...
What do you guys think?
About three leagues?
Well, that baby's going to float
you right past Sydney.
MARLIN: Great! That's great!
- Dory, you did it.
- Oh, please.
I'm just your little helper.
Helping along. That's me.
- Well, listen fellas, thank you.
- Don't mention it.
Just loosen up. Okay, buddy?
Oh, You guys!
You really nailed him. Bye.
- Oh. Hey, Ma'am. One more thing.
- Yes?
When you come to this trench,
swim through it, not over it.
Trench. Through it. Not over it.
I'll remember.
Hey, hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey, Wait up, partner. Hold on.
Wait, wait. I've got to tell
you something. Whoa.
Nice trench.
Hello! (ECHOING)
- Okay, Let's go.
- No, no. Bad trench. Bad trench.
- Come on. We're gonna swim over this thing.
- Whoa, partner. Little red flag going up.
Something's telling me
we should swim through it, not over it.
Are you even looking at this thing?
It's got death written all over it.
I'm sorry, but I really, really,
really think we should swim through.
And I'm really, really, really done
talking about this. Over we go.
Come on. Trust me on this.
- Trust you?
- Yes. Trust. It's what friends do.
- Look! Something shiny!
- Where?
It just swam over the trench.
Come on. We'll follow it. Okay.
- Boy, it sure is clear up here.
- Exactly.
And look at that.
There's the current.
We should be there in no time.
- Hey, little guy.
- You wanted to go through the trench.
I shall call him Squishy and he shall
be mine. And he shall be my squishy.
Come here, Squishy.
Come here, little Squishy.
(MUMBLING)
- Ow!
- Dory.
- That's a jellyfish! Shoo!
- Bad Squishy. Bad Squishy.
Shoo! Shoo! Get away.
- Come here. Let me see that.
- Don't touch it. Don't touch it.
I'm not gonna touch it.
I just want to look.
Hey, how come
it didn't sting you?
- It did. It's just that... Hold still.
- Ow! Ow, ow.
I live in this anemone and I'm used
to these kind of stings. Come here.
It doesn't look bad.
You're going to be fine.
But now we know, don't we? That
we don't want to touch these again.
Let's be thankful this time
it was just a little one.
Don't move.
- This is bad, Dory.
- Hey, watch this.
- Boing. Boing.
- Dory!
- You can't catch me.
Don't bounce on the tops.
They will...
not sting you!
- The tops don't sting you. That's it.
- DORY: Two in a row. Beat that.
Dory. All right, listen to me.
I have an idea.
- A game. A game.
- A game? A game?
Oh, I love games. Pick me.
Here's the game. Whoever can hop the
fastest out of these jellyfish wins.
- Okay! Okay.
- Rules. Rules, rules.
You can't touch the tentacles.
Only the tops.
Something about tentacles.
Got it. On your Mark. Get set. Go!
Wait! Not something about them.
It's all about them. Wait, Dory!
Gotta go faster
if you want to win.
- Dory!
- Boing, boing, boing!
Wait a minute, Dory!
Whee!
So, we're cheating death now.
That's what we're doing.
We're having fun at the same time.
- I can do this. Just be careful.
- Yeah.
Careful I don't make
you cry when I win.
Oh, I don't think so!
Give it up, old man. You can't fight
evolution. I was built for speed.
- The question is, Dory. Are you hungry?
- Hungry?
Yeah. 'Cause you're about
to eat my bubbles!
Duck to the left, back and
coming over, right there!
The clownfish is the winner!
Whoohoo!
We did it. Look at us!
Dory?
Oh, no.
Dory! Dory! Dory!
Dory!
(SIZZLING)
(MARLIN SCREAMING, GROANING)
DORY: Am I disqualified?
No, You're doing fine.
You're actually winning.
You gotta stay awake. Where does
P. Sherman live?
P. Sherman,
Wallaby Way, Sydney.
That's it!
Stay awake. Stay awake.
Stay awake.
Stay awake!
- (WEAKLY) Awake...
- P. Sherman...
- Awake...
- 42 Wallaby Way...
- Wake up.
- Sydney.
MARLIN: Nemo...
You Miss your dad,
don't you, Sharkbait?
Yeah.
Well, you're lucky to have someone
out there who's looking for you.
He's not looking for me.
He's scared of the ocean.
Peach? Any movement?
He's had atleast four cups of coffee.
It's got to be soon.
Keep on him.
My first escape, landed
on dental tools.
- I was aiming for the toilet.
- The toilet?
All drains lead
to the ocean, kid.
Wow. How many times have
you tried to get out?
I've lost count. Fish aren't meant to be
in a box, kid. It does things to you.
The bubbles, the bubbles!
Potty break! Potty break! He just grabbed
the Reader's Digest. We have 4.2 minutes.
That's your cue, Sharkbait.
- You can do it, kid.
- Okay. We got to be quick.
Once you get in, you swim down to the bottom
of the chamber and I'll talk you through the rest.
Okay.
- Go on. It'll be a piece of kelp.
- (INHALES DEEPLY)
- Nicely done. Can you hear me?
- Yeah.
Here comes the pebble.
- Now, do you see a small opening?
- Uh-huh.
Okay. Inside it
you'll see a rotating fan.
Very carefully, wedge that pebble
into the fan to stop it turning.
Easy, easy.
Careful, Sharkbait.
- I can't do it.
- Gill, this isn't a good idea.
He'll be fine. Try again!
Okay.
GILL: That's it, Sharkbait.
Nice and steady.
- I got it, I got it!
- He did it.
That's great, kid.
Now, swim up the tube and out.
Oh, no! Gill! Gill!
- Sharkbait! Get him out of there!
- Oh, my gosh. Get him out of there!
- Help him!
- What do we do? What do we do?
- Oh, no!
- Stay calm, kid. Just don't panic.
- Help me!
- Sharkbait, grab hold of this.
No, no!
- Feed me more.
- That's it!
Come on, Sharkbait. Grab it.
- I got it.
- Pull!
Gill, don't make him
go back in there.
No. We're done.
(WHIMPERING)
CRUSH: Dude?
Dude?
Focus, dude.
Oh, he lives. Hey, dude.
(MARLIN GROANS)
- What happened?
- I saw the whole thing, dude.
First you were all, like, whoa!
And then we were all, like, whoa!
- Then you were, like, whoa...
- What are you talking about?
You, mini-man! Taking on the jellies.
You got serious thrill issues, dude.
Awesome.
Oh, my stomach.
Oh, man, no hurling on the shell, dude.
Okay? I just waxed it.
- So, Mr. Turtle...
- Whoa. Dude, Mr. Turtle is my father.
Name's Crush.
Crush? Really?
Okay, Crush.
Listen, I need to get to the
East Australian Current.
EAC?
Dude...
You're riding it, dude.
Check it out.
Okay, grab shell, dude.
Grab what?
Ho-ho! Righteous! Righteous!
So,
what brings you on this
fine day to the EAC?
Well, Dory and I need
to get to Sydney.
Dory? Dory!
Is she all right?
Oh, little blue.
She is sub-level, dude.
Dory, Dory! Dory!
Oh, Dory.
(DORY MUMBLES INCOHERENTLY)
I'm so sorry.
This is all my fault.
It's my fault.
Twenty-nine, 30!
Ready or not, here I come!
There you are.
Catch me if you can.
Up you go!
(LAUGHTER)
Oh, my goodness.
Kill the motor, dude. Let us see
what Squirt does flying solo.
Whoa! That was so cool.
Hey, Dad. Did you see that?
Did you see me?
- Did you see what I did?
- You so totally rock, Squirt.
Give me some fin.
Noggin.
Dude.
Intro. Jellyman, Offspring.
Offspring, Jellyman.
- Jellies? Sweet.
- Totally.
Well, apparently. I must have done
something you all liked, dudes.
- You rock, dude.
- Ow.
Curl away, my son.
It's awesome, Jellyman.
When the little dudes are eggs we
leave them on a beach to hatch,
and coo-coo-cachoo, they find their
way back to the big ol' blue.
- All by themselves?
- Yeah!
But, dude, how do you
know when they're ready?
Well, you never really know, but when
they know, you'll know. You know?
(LAUGHTER)
- Hey, look, everybody.
- I know that dude.
It's the Jellyman.
- Well go on. Jump on him.
- Turtle pile!
Wait. Kids!
- Are you funny?
- Where's your shell?
- Do your stripes come off?
- I need to breathe.
Did you really cross
the jellyfish Forest?
- One at a time.
- Mr. Fish, did you die?
Sorry. I was a little vague
on the details.
- So where are you going?
- Well, you see, my son was taken.
My son was
taken away from me.
- No way!
- What happened?
No, no, kids. I don't want
to talk about it.
- Aw, Come on.
- Please.
Well, okay.
I live on this reef,
a long, long way from here.
Oh, boy. This is gonna be
good. I can tell.
And my son, Nemo.
He was mad at me.
Maybe he wouldn't have done it if
I hadn't been so tough on him.
I don't know.
Anyway, he swam out in the open
water to this boat
and when he was out there these divers
appeared and I tried to stop them.
The boat was too fast, so
we swam out in the ocean...
He couldn't stop them.
Then Nemo's dad,
he swims out to the ocean
and they bump into
three ferocious sharks.
He scares away the sharks
by blowing them up.
- God, that's amazing.
- And then dives thousands of feet...
Straight down into the dark. It's like wicked
dark down there. You can't see a thing.
How's it going, Bob? And the only thing
they can see down there is...
This big, horrible creature with
razor-sharp teeth! Nice parry, old man.
Then he has to blast his way...
These fish have been
searching the ocean for days
on the East Australian Current.
I suppose, he may be
on his way here right now.
That should put him
in Sydney Harbour...
In a matter of days.
I mean, It sounds like this guy's
not gonna stop at nothing...
stop at nothing until he finds
his son. I sure hope he makes it.
That's one dedicated father,
if you ask me.
Mine. Mine. Mine.
Oh, would you just shut up?
- You're rats with wings. Nemo?
- This bloke's been looking for his boy, Nemo.
- He was taken off the reef by divers...
- There. Take it.
Hey, hey. Say that again. You just
said something about Nemo. What was it?
Mine. Mine. Mine.
(GROWLS)
Mine.
Last I heard, he's heading
towards the harbour.
Brilliant!
Is he doing okay?
I don't know, but whatever
you do, don't mention D-A-R...
It's okay. I know who
you're talking about.
Gill? Gill?
Hey, Sharkbait.
- I'm sorry I couldn't stop...
- GILL: I'm the one who should be sorry.
I was so ready to get out,
so ready to taste that ocean,
I was willing to put you in
harm's way to get there.
Nothing should be worth that.
I'm sorry I couldn't get you
back to your father, kid.
All right. Hey, hey, hey!
- What the...
- (PATIENT SCREAMS)
Well, that's one way
to pull a tooth. (LAUGHS)
Darn kids. Well, good thing
I pulled the right one, eh?
Hey, hey. Pssst!
Oh, Nigel, you just
missed an extraction.
Has he loosened the
periodontal ligament yet?
What am I talking about?
Nemo. Where's Nemo?
- I've got to speak with him.
- What? What is it?
Your dad's been fighting
the ocean looking for you.
- My father? Really?
- Oh, wow!
Oh, yeah. He's travelled
hundreds of miles.
- He's been battling sharks and jellyfish.
- Sharks?
- That can't be him.
- Are you sure? What was his name?
Some sort of sport fish or something.
Tuna? A Trout?
- Marlin?
- That's it. Marlin.
- The little clownfish from the reef.
- It's my dad! He took on a shark!
- I heard he took on three.
- Three?
- Three sharks?
- That's got to be 4,800 teeth!
You see kid. After
you were taken by Diver Dan,
your dad followed the
boat all over like a maniac.
- Really?
- He's swimming.
He's swimming. He's giving it all he's got and
then three gigantic sharks captured him.
He blows 'em up and then
dives thousands of feet
and gets chased by a
monster with huge teeth!
He ties this demon to a rock.
And what does he get for a reward?
He gets to battle an entire
jellyfish Forest.
And now he's riding with a bunch of
sea turtles on the East Australian Current
and the word is he's headed
this way, right now, to Sydney!
- Oh, What a good daddy.
- He was looking for you after all, Sharkbait.
- He's swimming in the filter!
- Not again!
Sharkbait!
- No!
- You've got your life ahead of you.
- We'll help you, kid.
- Gotta get him out.
- Get him out of there.
- Come on, kid. Grab the end.
(GEAR JAMS)
- Sharkbait!
- Sharkbait, are you okay?
Can you hear me, Sharkbait?
Nemo? Can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you.
Sharkbait, you did it!
Sharkbait, you're...
Covered with germs!
That took guts, kid.
All right, gang. We have less than
48 hours before Darla gets here.
This tank will get plenty
dirty in that time,
but we have to help it along
anyway we can.
- Jacques, no cleaning.
- Oui. I shall resist.
GILL: Everybody else,
be as gross as possible.
Think dirty thoughts.
We're going to make this tank so filthy,
the dentist'll have to clean it.
- (BURPS)
- Good work.
All right, we're here, dudes.
Get ready! Your exit's
coming up, man.
- Where? I don't see it.
- Right there. I see it. I see it.
- You mean the swirling vortex of terror?
- That's it, dude.
- Of course it is.
- Okay. First, find your exit buddy.
- Do you have your exit buddy?
- Yes.
Squirt here will now give you a
rundown on proper exiting technique.
Good afternoon. We're going
to have a great jump today.
Crank a hard cutback
as you hit the wall.
There's a screaming
bottom turn, so watch out.
Remember, rip it,
roll it and punch it!
It's like he's trying to
speak to me, I know it.
You're really cute, but I don't know what
you're saying. Say the first thing again.
Okay, Jellyman. Go, go, go!
- Whoa!
Whoo!
That was fun.
I actually enjoyed that.
Hey, look! Turtles.
Most excellent.
Now, turn your fishy tails round and
swim straight on through to Sydney.
No worries, man.
No worries. Thank you,
Dude Crush.
- ALL: Bye.
- Bye, Jellyman.
Tell your little dude
I said hi, okay?
- See ya later, dudes.
- DORY: Bye, everyone.
Oh, Nemo would've loved this.
Hey, Crush. Crush, I forgot.
How old are you?
CRUSH: 150, dude!
And still young. Rock on!
150. 150.
I got to remember that.
Whoa.
- We going in there?
- Yep.
P. Sherman, 42
Wallaby Way, Sydney?
Yep.
We're going to just
swim straight.
♪ Just keep swimming  ♪
MARLIN: Dory...
MARLIN: Boy,
this is taking a while.
DORY: Hey, how about
we play a game?
MARLIN: Okay.
Okay, I'm thinking
of something orange.
- And it's small...
- It's me.
Right.
This one you'll never guess.
It's orange and small.
It's me.
All righty, Mr. Smarty Pants.
It's orange and small
and white stripes...
Me. And the next one,
just a guess, me.
Okay. That's just scary.
Wait. I have definitely seen this
floating speck before.
That means we've passed it before.
And that means we're going circles.
That means we're not
going straight.
We got to get to the surface.
We'll figure it out there. Let's go. Follow me.
- Hey! Hey!
- What?
Relax. Take a deep breath.
Now, let's ask somebody
for directions.
Oh, Fine. Who do you want to ask?
The speck? There's nobody here!
Well, there has to be someone.
It's the ocean. Silly.
We're not the only two in here.
Let's see...
Okay, no one there.
Nope.
Nada.
- There's somebody. Hey, excu...
- Dory! Dory!
Okay. Now, It's my turn. I'm thinking
of something dark and mysterious.
It's a fish we don't know, and if we ask directions,
it could ingest us. And spit out our bones!
What is it with men and
asking for directions?
Oh, I don't want to play the gender card
right now. Let's play the "let's not die" card.
- You want to get out of here?
- Of course I do.
How are we going to do that unless we
give it a shot and hope for the best?
- You don't fully understand.
- Come on. Trust me on this.
All right.
Excuse me? Whoo-hoo!
Little fella?
Hello.
Don't be rude. Say hi.
- His son Bingo...
- Nemo.
- ...was taken to...
- Sydney.
Sydney, yes.
And It's really, really important that
we get there as fast as we can.
So, can you help us out?
Come on, little fella. Come on.
Dory, I'm a little fella.
I don't think that's
a little fella.
Big fella. Whale. Okay.
Maybe he only speaks whale.
(IMITATING WHALE)
We need...
- to find his son.
- Uh, Dory? What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Are you sure you speak whale?
Can you give us...
- Heaven knows what you're saying.
- ... Directions?
- MARLIN: See, he's swimming away.
- Come back.
He's not coming back.
You've offended him.
Maybe a different dialect.
(MOOING)
Dory, this is not whale.
You're speaking, like, upset stomach.
- Maybe I should try humpback.
- No, don't try humpback.
(GROWLING)
- You actually sound sick.
- Maybe louder, huh?
- Don't do that.
- Too much orca.
- Didn't that sound a little orca-ish?
- It sounds like nothing I've ever heard.
- (MOOING)
- (GROANS)
Just as well.
He might be hungry.
Don't worry. Whales don't eat
clownfish. They eat krill.
- KRILLS: Swim away!
- Oh, look. Krill!
Move, Dory! Move!
Look at that.
Would you look at that?
Filthy. Absolutely filthy.
And it's all thanks to you, kid.
You made it possible.
Jacques, I said no cleaning.
I am ashamed.
Look. Scum Angel.
(WHIMPERING)
Bubbles! I love the bubbles.
(COUGHING)
Flo? Has anybody seen Flo? Flo!
9:00 o'clock,
and cue dentist.
Hello, Barbara. Sorry I'm late.
Okay. Okay, here we go.
Here we go. Okay.
Little Davey Reynolds.
- Walks to the counter, drops the keys...
- Bloat, that's disgusting.
Tastes pretty good to me.
(BURPS)
Don't you people realise
we are swimming in our own...
- Shh! Here he comes.
- What the...
Crikey. What a state.
Barbara, what's my earliest
appointment tomorrow?
- 10:00 o'clock, love.
- Leave it open, would you?
I've got to clean the fish
tank before Darla gets here.
- Did you hear that, Sharkbait?
- Yay! He's going to clean the tank!
Yeah, we're going to be clean!
- You ready to see your dad?
- Uh-huh.
'Course you are.
I wouldn't be surprised if he's out there
in the harbour waiting for you right now.
Yeah.
(YELLING)
(DORY LAUGHS HAPPILY)
DORY: Whoo!
Here comes a big one! Come on.
You got to try this.
- MARLIN: Will you just stop it?
- Why? What's wrong?
- We're in a whale. Don't you get it?
- A whale?
A whale! 'Cause you had to ask for
help. And now we're stuck here.
- A whale? You know, I speak whale.
- No, you're insane. You can't speak whale.
I have to get out.
I have to find my son.
I have to tell him how
old sea turtles are!
(DESPAIRING GROAN)
(DORY WHOOPING)
Hey.
You okay?
There, there.
It's all right. It'll be okay.
No. No, It won't.
Sure it will. You'll see.
No. I promised him I'd never
let anything happen to him.
Huh. That's a funny
thing to promise.
What?
Well, you can't never let
anything happen to him.
Then nothing would
ever happen to him.
Not much fun for little Harpo.
- What's going on?
- Don't know. I'll ask him.
- (MOOS) What's...
- Dory.
- Going...
on?
(WHALE ROARS)
- I think he says we've stopped.
- Of course we've stopped.
Stop trying to speak whale.
You're gonna make things worse.
What is that noise?
(ROARING)
Oh, no. Look what you did.
The water's going down.
It's going down!
- Really? You sure about that?
- Look. Already it's half-empty.
- Hmm. I'd say it's half-full.
- Stop that. It's half-empty!
(ROARING)
Okay, that one was
a little tougher.
He either said we should go
to the back of the throat
or he wants a root beer float.
Of course he wants us
to go there. That's eating us!
How do I taste, Moby?
Huh? Do I taste good?
You tell him I'm not
interested in being lunch.
- Okay. He's...
- Stop talking to him.
- What is going on?
- I'll check. What...
No. No more whale.
You can't speak whale.
Yes, I can.
No, you can't.
You think you can do these
things, but you can't, Nemo.
(ROARING AND WHISTLING)
- Okay.
- Dory!
He says it's time to let go.
Everything's going
to be all right.
How do you know?
How do you know something
bad isn't going to happen?
I don't!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(CACKLES)
We're alive!
Look. Syd-ney.
Sydney! Sydney.
Sydney again.
You were right, Dory. We made it!
We're going to find my son.
Thank you, Sir.
Wow. I wish I could speak whale.
Okay. All we gotta do,
is find the board that took him.
- Right.
- Come on, Dory. We can do this!
(YAWNS)
Morning. It's morning, everyone.
Today's the day. The sun is shining, the
tank is clean and we are getting out of...
(GASPS)
The tank is clean.
The tank is clean!
But how?
Boss must have installed it
last night, while we were sleeping.
- What are we going to do?
- What's it say, Peach?
(MUFFLED VOICE)
I can't hear you, Peach.
The Aqua Scum 2003 is an all-purpose,
self-cleaning maintenance free salt-water purifier
that is guaranteed even extends
the life of your aquarium fish.
Stop it!
The Aqua Scum is programmed to
scan your tank environment every five minutes?
Scan? What does that mean?
AUTOMATED VOICE: Temperature
82 degrees, PH balance normal.
ALL: Oooh!
Nice.
Curse you, Aqua Scum!
- That's it for the escape plan. It's ruined.
- Then what are we going to do about...
ALL: (GASPS) Darla!
Stay down, kid.
- False alarm.
- My nerves can't take much more of this.
BLOAT: What are we going to
do when that little brat gets here?
- I'm thinking, I'm thinking.
- NEMO: No! Help!
- Help me! Help me!
- Hold on. I'm coming.
Help me!
Swim down! Come on, kid.
Swim down! Come on.
- Everybody jump in. That's it.
- Swim down!
What the...
Good work.
- Gill!
- Sharkbait!
- Roll, kid! Lean, kid! Roll!
- Go to the window.
DR. PHILIP: Whoops! That would
have been a nasty fall.
- Gill, I don't want to go belly-up!
- Just calm down, Nemo.
You won't go belly-up.
I promise.
You're going to be okay.
ALL: (GASPS) Darla!
Do any of these boats
look familiar to you?
No, but the boat has
to be here somewhere.
- Come on, Dory. We're gonna find it.
- I'm totally excited.
- (YAWNS) Are you excited?
- Dory, wake up. Wake up. Come on.
Duck!
That's not a duck.
It's a pelican!
No! I didn't come this far
to be breakfast.
Hey. Hey, Nigel.
Would you look at that?
What?
Sun's barely up and already
Gerald's had more than he can handle.
Yeah. Reckon somebody ought
to help the poor guy.
(MURMURS OF AGREEMENT)
Well, don't everybody
fly off at once!
(RETCHES)
All right, Gerald. What is it?
Fish got your tongue?
Love a duck!
I've got to find my son Nemo.
Nemo?
He's that fish the one we've been talking about
that's been fighting the whole ocean.
Hey, I know
where your son...
Hey, wait. Come back.
- Stop!
- Don't. Keep going. He's crazy.
I've got something to tell you.
Mine.
Okay. Don't make
any sudden moves.
Hop inside my mouth
if you want to live.
Hop in your mouth, huh?
And how does that make me live?
- Mine?
- Because I can take you to your son.
Yeah, right!
No. I know your son. He's orange.
He's got a gimpy fin on one side.
- That's Nemo!
- Mine! Mine! Mine!
Fasten your seat belts!
Mine! Mine! Mine!
DORY: Whoo-hoo!
Everybody hold on!
Mine! Mine! Mine!
- (ALL SCREAMS)
- Too loud. Too loud for me.
♪ Twinkle, twinkle,
little star  ♪
Find a happy place.
Find a happy place!
BARBARA: Darla,
your uncle will see you now.
All right. Let's see
those Pearly whites.
I'm a piranha.
There in the Amazon.
And a piranha's a fish.
Just like your present.
- DARLA: I got a fishy!
- Oh, no.
Poor little guy.
- He's dead.
- Sharkbait!
Yay! Fishy, fishy, fishy!
Must have left your present in the
car, sweetie. I'll go and get it.
He's still alive!
What's happening?
Why is he playing dead?
He's going to get flushed
down the toilet.
He's going to get out of here.
- What a smart little guy.
- Oh, no. Not the trash can!
Hey! I found his dad.
- Where's Nemo? Where is he?
- Dentist! Dentist!
- He's over there.
- What's a dentist? What is that?
- Nigel, get in there.
- I can't go in there.
Oh, yes you can. Charge!
- (SCREAMS)
- What the...
Darla, sweetie, look out.
Hold still. Hold still.
Easy, easy.
Hold still!
It's all right. Nobody's
going to hurt you.
Nemo.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Gotcha!
- MARLIN: Nemo!
- Daddy?
DR. PHILIP: Out with you.
And stay out!
- Daddy?
- Fishy?
Fishy!
Wake up! Wake up!
- Oh, no!
- Quick! To the top...
of Mount Wannahockaloogie.
Why are you sleeping?
- Hurry!
- Bloat!
Ring of Fire!
Fishy!
- DARLA: Get it out!
- Crikey!
All the animals
have gone mad!
DARLA: (SCREAMS)
Get it out!
- Smack her in the head!
- Go, Gill, go!
There's a fish in my hair!
- Gill.
- Sharkbait.
Tell your dad I said hi.
(SCREAMS)
- Go get him.
- (DR. PHILIP GROANS)
He did it!
- I'm so happy.
- Is he going to be okay, Gill?
Don't worry. All drains
lead to the ocean.
Fishy!
(SCREAMING)
Daddy!
(GASPS, WHIMPERS)
I'm... I'm so sorry.
Truly I am.
- Hey...
- Dory.
If it wasn't for you, I never
would have even made it here.
So thank you.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait. Where are you going?
It's over, Dory.
We were too late.
Nemo's gone.
I'm going home now.
No. No, you can't.
Stop!
Please don't go away. Please?
No one's ever stuck with
me for so long before.
And if you leave...
If you leave...
I just... I remember things
better with you. Look.
P. Sherman, 42...
42...
(GROANS) I remember it. I do.
It's there. I know it is.
Because when I look at you,
I can feel it.
And I look at you and I...
I'm home.
Please. I don't want
that to go away.
I don't want to forget.
I'm sorry, Dory,
but I do.
- Manna from heaven.
- Sweet nectar of life.
- Hey!
- Hey! Hey!
- This is our spot.
- Go on. Get out of here.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Hey, hey!
Yeah, that's it fella. Just keep
on swimmin'. You got that?
Too right, mate!
Oh, oh! I got a live one here!
- Wait. Have you seen my dad?
- Gotcha!
- Come back here.
- You let him go!
Dad!
DORY: No!
(DORY GROANS)
- Excuse me.
- No.
- Are you all right?
- I don't know where I am.
I don't know what's going on.
I think I lost somebody,
but I can't remember.
- It's okay.
- I can't remember.
I'm looking for someone, too.
Hey, we can look together.
- I'm Dory.
- I'm Nemo.
Nemo?
That's a nice name.
- Dad!
- Dad.
Wait a minute.
Is it your dad or my dad?
My dad.
- Got it. Dad!
- Where are we anyway?
Dad!
Huh. Syl... Schai...
Sydney.
P. Sherman, 42
Wallaby Way, Sydney.
- Nemo!
- What?
It's you! Nemo!
Yes, yes. I'm Nemo.
You're Nemo. You were dead.
I saw you.
And then... Here you are.
I found you, and you're not dead.
And your father... Your father!
My father? You know my father?
Where is he?
He went this way. Quick!
- DORY: Hey, hey, hey!
- CRABS: Hey, hey, hey!
Have you seen an
orange fish swim by?
- It looks just like him.
- But bigger.
Yeah, I saw him, but I'm not
telling you where he went.
And there's no way
you're going to make me.
Mine.
(SCREAMS)
All right. I'll talk! I'll talk.
He went to the fishing grounds.
- Hey, look out.
- Sorry.
I'm just trying to get home.
NEMO: (INDISTINCT) Daddy!
- Nemo?
- NEMO: Daddy!
Nemo?
- NEMO: Dad!
- DORY: Nemo's alive!
Dory?
- Nemo!
- Daddy!
- Nemo! I'm coming, Nemo!
- Dad!
Nemo! Oh, thank goodness.
It's all right, son.
It's going to be okay.
FISH: Turn around!
You're going the wrong way.
- (SCREAMS) Look out!
- Move!
(DORY SCREAMS)
- Dory!
- Come on.
Help! Get us out!
No, no, no! Dory!
- Dad, I know what to do.
- Nemo, no!
We have to tell all the
fish to swim down together.
- Get out of there now!
- I know this will work.
No, I am not
gonna lose you again.
Dad, there's no time.
It's the only way we can save Dory.
I can do this!
You're right. I know you can.
- NEMO: Lucky fin.
- Now, go. Hurry!
Tell all the fish to swim down.
Well, you heard my son. Come on.
- Dory, you have to tell everybody to...
- Swim down together.
Do you understand
what I'm saying to you?
Swim down!
- Everybody swim down. Swim down, Okay?
- Come on. You have to swim down.
Down! Swim down!
Swim down! Swim down!
Don't give up! Keep swimming!
Just keep swimming!
MARLIN: That's it!
It's working!
ALL: Keep swimming!
Just keep swimming!
- Come on, Dad!
- You're doing great, son.
- That's my dad.
- How about we get to the bottom.
♪ Just keep swimming,
Just keep swimming ♪
MARLIN: Almost there.
Keep swimming!
ALL: Keep swimming!
(ALL FISHES CHEERING)
- Hey!
- Dory!
Where's Nemo?
There!
Oh, no. Nemo!
Nemo?
It's okay. Daddy's here.
Daddy's got you.
- Daddy?
- Oh, thank goodness.
Daddy...
- I don't hate you.
- Oh, no, no, no.
I'm so sorry, Nemo.
Hey, guess what?
- What?
- Sea turtles...
I met one.
And he was 150 years old.
150?
Yep.
'Cause Sandy Plankton said
they only lived to be 100.
Sandy Plankton?
Think I would cross the ocean and
not know as much as Sandy Plankton?
He was 150! Not 100.
Who is this Sandy Plankton
that knows everything wrong?
Time for school! Time for school!
Get up! Let's go! Let's go!
- I'm going to win.
- No, you're not.
- I did it.
- Oh, my own son beats me.
Climb aboard, explorers.
So jsut then the sea cucumber looks
over at the mollusk and says,
"With fronds like these,
who needs anemones?"
Well, hello, Nemo. Who's this?
- Exchange student.
- I'm from the EAC, dude.
- Sweet.
- Totally.
Seriously, Marty, did you really
do all the things you say you did?
BRUCE: Pardon me.
Hello.
Don't be alarmed.
We just wanted to make sure our
newest member got home safely.
- Thanks guys.
- We'll see you next week.
- Keep up with the programme, Dory.
- Remember, fish are friends.
Not food! Bye!
Hold on. Here we go.
Next stop, knowledge.
Bye, son. Have fun.
NEMO: Bye, Dad.
Oh! Mr. Ray, wait.
I forgot something.
Love you, Dad.
I love you, too, son.
Uh, Dad? You can let go now.
Sorry.
Now go have an adventure.
Goodbye. See you later, dudes!
- Bye, Elmo.
- Nemo.
- Nemo. Bye, Nemo.
- See you after school, Dory.
NEMO: Bye, Dad!
Bye, son.
DR. PHILIP: Barbara.
BARBARA: Mmm-hmm?
I don't understand it.
Here this thing has a lifetime
guarantee and it breaks.
Had to clean the tank myself, take
the fish out, put 'em in bags and...
Where'd the fish go?
(CAR HORN HONKS)
- Come on, Peach!
- Hurry!
You got it. That's it.
You can do it.
That's the shortest red
light I've ever seen.
Come on, Peach.
(ALL CHEERING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
Now what?
(POP MUSIC PLAYING)